# José Gregorio Lezama González

# **Technical Lead & Web Developer**



https://joseglego.io/

# **Vargas, Venezuela**Remote & Willing to Relocate

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a **passionate developer** and a **coffee lover**.

As a developer, I have experience in **back-end** and **front-end**. I am interested in learning new technologies. I like to follow the best practices of each new language or framework. I enjoy front-end development, working with good eye for details and working for a good look and feel & UX. Also, I really like to work back-end. So, I can work full-stack.

My last works were in: Front-End & UX, Back-End, Web Mobile, a little of Automation & Admin.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Technical Lead & Developer**

**Cleteci** | Feb 2017 - Present

Mentoring a group of 7 - 9 developers, reviewing code and supporting them. Supporting QA team fixing issues related to next release and production. Investigation and of new tools & technologies to improve the quality of the environment, code and product. Defining higher standards for code, product & documentation. Supporting thirds companies integrations. Writing and Managing refactoring.

# **Scrum Master & Developer**

**Cleteci** | Jan 2016 - Jan 2017

Mentoring a group of 3 - 5 developers, reviewing code and supporting them. Supporting QA team fixing issues related to next release and production. Writing refactoring and including new tools and technologies.

# **Web Developer**

**Cleteci** | Sep 2014 - Dec 2015

Developing new features on RESTful APIS with clients applications and classic web applications.

# Web Developer & Architect

**Datos MEG** | Sep 2015 - Present

Working in a Web & Web Mobile app with a RESTful API server. I'm working as a developer / admin of multiple servers / architect / UX developer / software designer. I'm like a Ninja Developer.

## **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor in Computer Engineering**

Simón Bolívar University | Sep 2007 - Nov 2015

**Internship:** Web System for <u>AtrioSeguros</u> Agents (Insurance Company) - with Honors

**Specialization: 1.** Databases, **2.** Computer Graphics & **3.** Software Development Workshop: A Medical Emergencies Software, <u>iTriage</u> - Current Version.

**Electives:** 1. Mobile Development, 2. Software Methodologies, 3. & 4. A.I. on Robotics and on Video Games, 5. Computer Graphics on Video Games & 6. A.R.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **Travel Contact**

A travel management & Agency travel management *startup*. Rails, AngularJS and Ionic

#### Latch

A smart access system **startup.** AngularJS

#### Phoebe

A photo studio sales app. Django & jQuery

# **Atrio Seguros**

A Insurance Agents app. AngularJS, Oracle & Java EE

## **Datos MEG**

A RESTful API with web and web mobile clients. Django + DRF, Ionic and AngularJS

# **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

# **Seller App**

A Menu and sales app. AngularJS

### **Attendance App**

Calculator. AngularJS and angular-charts

## **TECHNOLOGIES & TOOLS** | Preferences on Bold

#### **Base**

**OS X - Linux**, Windows, **Python**, **Javascript**, **Ruby**, Java, C/C++, Bash, Haskell, Prolog.

### Web

AngularJS, Gulp, Bower, HTML, CSS, JS, Lodash, jQuery, Bootstrap, Grunt, Django, Ruby on Rails, Node, Express.

# **Tools**

Ionic/Phonegap, Emacs, PostgreSQL, SQLite3, git, Photoshop, Illustrator, Agile/Scrum, Heroku, AWS, Linode, DigitalOcean.

### **OTHER ACTIVITIES**

Daily English Lessons, 3 hours. | Aug 2016 - Present

Urban Data Fest (<u>Venezuela</u>): 3rd Place, <u>Monitorea.la</u>: front-end developer | Mar 2015

CodeSchool: Courses of JavaScript (10), Ruby (2), HTML/CSS (4) & others (3) | 2014 - Present

### **LANGUAGES**

**Spanish** - Native speaker **English** - Upper Intermediate